[Music]
this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se-
radio.net SC radio is brought to you by
the it computer society and by It
software Magazine online at computer.org
[Music]
software welcome to software engineering
radio I'm your host Gregory cap Hammer
today's guest is Marcelo trinsky a
senior software engineer at pantic along
with working on data validation and
cloud services identic Marcelo is a
maintainer of open-source python
projects like Starlet and uvicorn both
of which are Frameworks that are
leveraged by fast API that is the
subject of our talk today Marcelo
welcome to software engineering radio
hey man thank you very much it's great
to be here all right hey I'm so glad you
can join the conversation today we're
going to be talking about fast API we're
going to explore what fast API is how
python programmers use it and the
specific problems that it solves I think
the first appropriate question is from
your Vantage Point what is fast API fast
API it's a framework that's used to
build apis in Python it leverag type
hint and it's very fun to develop with
okay so you mentioned that it used
something called type hints or some
people call those type annotations can
you explain why that's one of the key
features of fast AP Pi the thing that's
cool is about the autoc completion so it
kind of enforces you to use the right
types CU you write on the signature of
the function you write the types that
you're going to use like the data you
receive
so you have a data validation happening
there so the type that you put it there
it's for sure the right one so one of
the things I know is that the word fast
means more than one thing so for example
the fast API website points out that it
is fast from a high performance
perspective and that in a way it's also
fast for me as a developer who's using
fast API can you comment on why fast API
is a web framework for building apis
that's fast in both of those Fashions so
for me I always saw as I mean even if
I'm the maintainer of uorn the server
that makes one of the reasons that fast
API to be fast on my perspective the
fast is more about the user perspective
because in any case you're still working
with python and there are certain
limitations but the idea is that since
you are leveraging the asyn io world you
don't need to use the threads so you can
have more tasks running in a single
thread and then you have more capacity
to run more tasks and that means that
you can receive and process more
requests that makes the server faster I
would say so we'll talk a little bit
later about the async approach that fast
API takes before we dive into those
technical details can you share an
example of a success story maybe like
for example another open- source project
or a company that uses fast API I know a
couple of companies that use fast API
that are like big companies also they
are mentioned on the first page of the
documentation like as a testimonial or
something you know I know that Netflix
has one project that's open source as
well I think it's called dispatch if you
look for dispatch Netflix on GitHub
you're going to find it I think that's
the most famous one that's open source
that is like really organized with
several modules and stuff so I would say
this one you also have as an example of
not a project that is running but you
have the full stack fast API that
Sebastian the creator of fast API has
just I wouldn't say rebranded but
refactored so it uses the latest
technologies that he believes should be
used with fast API so those two projects
I think they're nice but yeah I know
also Microsoft uses on some projects I
saw somewhere as well but yeah we use at
pantic as
well thanks for sharing those examples
we'll link to some of those in the show
notes for listeners who are interested
in diving in and learning more now
you'll recall I mentioned a moment ago
that fast API is for building these web
apis and I'm aware of the fact that
there are a whole bunch of different API
standards like the open API standard or
wsgi or asgi
can you help the listeners to understand
what some of these various standards are
and how fast API fits into this
ecosystem yeah sure so the open API
standard it's for defining how your API
looks like so it works only with HTTP
related methods so you don't have for
example event driven things events
happening on the like you you cannot
describe them on the open API spec so
for example Fest API also supports web
soof ET but you cannot describe them on
the open API because this standard like
this specification does not tells you a
way to specify how web socket looks like
but you can specify all the HTTP methods
like get post but you know so this is
one thing and but what you mentioned
about the USG and the asgi they are not
related with this standard they are more
about how you build the actually is the
interface how how you interface the
server and the application so uasi was
the python standard for many years and
it's also there's a b about it and it's
also there's also a package called UI on
the standard library that you can use to
test and create your uasg applications
but the asgi one which is kind of I
think I'm not sure if it's considered
new still because by now it has six
seven seven years I think it's from I
think from 2018 or 17 and it's just
defin as an interface for you to write
python web Frameworks mean the server
and the application leveraging a sync
python so you ask it without a syn ask
it with a sync thanks for that response
that was really helpful now you
mentioned that the a in asgi or asgi
stands for asynchronous and you
mentioned async previously can you
develop for the listeners a little bit
more what is the meaning of asynchronous
and why is that important in the context
of using fast API if you look at the how
things happen sequentially so the server
gets a request right and then it needs
to do something to send to the
application so in the UI world not the
ASI USI previously you had to create a
thread or use thread you had a thread
pool and then send and I mean you
process the the request that you're
receiving like you get the data and then
you pass that data to the application
via thread on this new ask world you
create a task and a sync task and then
You' pass the it's the same process but
instead of using a threat you're going
to use a task which for one reason it's
I'm not sure if it's easy to code with
but your application does run really
fast when you have multiple of those
running you use far less resources sure
that makes sense so there's a clear
benefit to this asynchronous approach
and I think this brings me to my next
question many of our listeners are
probably familiar with creating a rest
API or creating a graphql API and they
may have used both of those previously
does fast API support both of those or
does it only support one how does that
work for graphql it doesn't support
anymore some years ago I think what 3
years ago I'm not sure if it was me who
deated and removed but I'm sure I think
I was the one who approved the request
so we removed the support for native
graphql like the butin we remove it and
then we have a page on the Starlet
documentation where you can see
Alternatives and you can integrate with
it so the way it works that fast API
startlet and other as Frameworks they
have a way for you to attach attach or
bind new well also asy applications so
you can bind them together and then you
can well use different Frameworks in
your application so for example you can
use straberry which is a famous graphql
library and you can create an strawberry
and then you can use I don't know
exactly how you connect strawberry as if
something maybe but then you can use
strawberry with fast API later in the
show we're going to talk a little bit
about how a person would actually write
a fast API in Python but before we do
that I want to spend some time talking
about how fast API was actually
implemented I know that fast API uses a
bunch of different Frameworks and you've
mentioned some of them already like for
example Starlet but I wanted to begin
with something that I found really
unique about fast API which is that t
Tada I get automatic API documentation
how does that actually work can you
explain it in Greater detail but
actually I want to go back a bit in time
before that I'm going to tell you how
the idea come to exist so there is
actually a an issue for that ises like
October
2018 FS API was created December 2018 so
two months after this issue so this
issue was created in Starlet where Tom
Christie the creator of Starlet and also
Yorn and hpx MK dogs all of those he
wanted to discuss about if and how to
map the schema the open API schema in
Starlet and then Sebastian saw that and
he mentioned what he wanted for like for
framework not necessarily for fast API
because at that point fast API didn't
exist and on that issue he wrote a huge
comment it's like really huge where you
can see the ideas that fast API had for
fast API time didn't have that name so
it didn't have any name because it
didn't exist but then Sebastian put
there that he wanted the automatic
documentation he wanted validation on
the input on the output he wanted the
features that you are you currently see
in in the current fast API also those
ideas I don't think they changed since
the beginning I think the ideas that I
written on this issue still are present
on the framework and yeah I can also
send you the link so you can share with
everybody with this old issue but yeah
you ask me about how it works in great
detail the open API generation the
schema generation so the way it works is
on each fast API endpoint so you have
the you have the endpoint function and
you have the signature of the function
right so the idea is that fast API will
inspect every endpoint function and it
will retrieve the signature like gets a
signature and from the signature it will
get from the parameters and from the
return statement it to get those types
and it will compute the open API Json
schema at the end so you get each
function and then you compute and then
you generate the the open API schema
right one thing is that you can add some
metadata and some more information so if
you have if you know like every endpoint
function you have The Decorator app Dot
and the method there you can add some
metadata for example you can add the how
the responses look like because for
example you have an HTTP exception in
the body and it's a 4 Z4 I don't know
and then you can write on this responses
uh parameter on The Decorator how that
looks like because if it's in the body
of the function there is no way you can
leverage type hint so you need to write
those on The Decorator so those are also
being taken in consideration in the
beginning of the application well after
Computing all the information that you
added on the metadata from the fast API
class from the API router and from The
Decorator and from the signature of the
functions itself and it generates this
open API Json and then so you have now
the open API Json and what you want and
what fast API does is to create for you
the Swagger page or the redock page both
of them are created automatically if you
don't change any settings you have them
out of the box in fast API okay so you
mentioned it has a Swagger UI or a redo
to be very clear what is swag UI and
what is redoc and if I was a person who
was using a fast API what would I see on
my screen okay so on the Swagger well
you see a page where we document all the
endpoints that fast API has all the
endpoints HTP endpoints let's call it
like that not the websockets so You' see
multiple entries describing what method
it is and the path to reach that method
and then it also defines how the base
URL how it is and then with that
information you can reach the the
endpoint also you can check the query
params the body params the path prams
that you can send to the application and
on Swagger the nice thing is that you
can interact with your with the
application so you can actually try the
input and then try and and see what the
server sends back yeah thank you for
that response I have to say that's one
of my favorite features of swagger that
I can actually interact with the API
directly through my web interface I also
wanted to say thank you for giving us
that historical perspective before
because I think that'll help our
listeners to understand a little bit
more about how this fast API system came
into existence yeah what I want to do
quickly now is to talk about the fact
that fast API has to perform input
conversion and it also has to perform
output conversion can you tell us a
little bit more about what those two
things are and how that happens in fast
API for example I said that you have the
par on the endpoint function right so
imagine you have this item class that
you define two fields for example name
and age I could have call it person I
know but anyway you have this class and
then you send a Json that instead of the
age being an integer then it's a string
potato then what's going to happen is
that the fast API it's going to try to
instantiate this item and then it's not
going to be able it's going to have a
validation error and then the client is
going to receive a 422 processable
entity and it's going to see the
response like there is an error here on
this field it is supposed to be an INT
but you actually send a string potato so
and then the client is able to
understand what's wrong and then can
send it the right information to the
server that was really helpful since you
just mentioned input validation a moment
ago let's dive in and talk about that in
Greater detail I'm aware of the fact
that fast API uses pantic for in input
validation at the very start can you
tell us what is pantic pantic well it's
a company I'm working on we have an open
source project with the same name and
the package does data validation SLP
parsing SL cision there is a lot of
discussion about what it really does in
terms of the the wording like if it's
cision if it's parsing if it's
validation but I think Samuel the
Creator I think accepted already the
name validation for it what it does so
it's a way that you can be sure that the
type you are writing in the classes they
are actually the types you are writing
so it's making sure that their typing is
what expected at run time that's pretty
much what it is I know one of the key
features of version 2.0 of pantic is
that it's now implemented in Rust can
you tell us a little bit more about how
you made the decision to use rust and
then perhaps talk a little bit about the
benefits associated with implement
pantic in Rust I can talk a bit about it
but I don't know all the details the
decision was made before I joined the
company and before I knew all the
information but yeah I can talk a bit so
what it happened differently than V1 is
that right now on V2 we build a schema I
think we call it pantic schema and then
what happens that we generate this
schema and then this schema is
regenerating in Rust so every time we
instantiate a ident IC class then we go
to the schema and then we validate our
data and that part of the schema is done
in in Rust so the benefit of using rust
is that you see a performance
Improvement in fast API is that correct
yes it is correct I can talk a bit more
about performance if like there are
several things that will impact the
performance but yeah changing 2v2 will
increase the performance of a fpi
application okay I also wanted to talk
about some framework I know you have
significant interest in and that you're
a maintainer of so for example fast API
uses something called uvicorn and
Starlet can you tell us a little bit
more I know we mentioned asgi servers
but if you could fit in uvicorn to what
we've discussed and then talk about
Starlet which you mentioned before I
think it might help our listeners to
understand the bigger picture of the
Frameworks that fast API uses so once
again the specs called asgi and uorn is
as server which runs applications that
looks like and follow the interface of
asgi so for example not not only fast
API but related ASI web Frameworks so
for example Starlet which is a web
framework as well so fast APN uorn can
run all of them the benefit of using
uorn is that it leverages the youth Loop
so it's a an event Loop implementation
that is faster than the one provided by
the standard Library so faster than the
hko and it also uses HTP tools which is
a HP parsing library that is a binding
for uh C library that right now I forgot
the name but it's the same one that's
nodejs uses it so node node uses a
binding as well and HTP tools is it's a
binding for the same C library and yeah
UF cor is just a web server and Starlet
oh there are also other web servers that
are in in this world but uicorn is by
far the most famous one there is one
called hyper corn or hyper corn I don't
know how f pronounces it the greater but
it's also very good implementation the
difference between those two servers is
that one uses streams so in Python you
have for creating web servers you have
protocol and the other one is with
streaming so eorn is with streams so
it's more on higher level so that's why
eorn has for example support Trio is
another async library that is very
famous that uses a structured how do you
call it structured programming no
structured concurrence yeah structur
concurrency I think that's the name but
then yeah uorn is uses protocols which
is a lower level and then that's why
it's also one of the reasons that is
fast than eorn and also you asked me
about Starlet right Starlet is a web
framework that is the provides all the
web capab abilities for fast API so
everything that is about that the first
step to go back to uorn so the way it
happens is like the client sends a
request uorn passes the request sends to
the web framework fast API so everything
in the middle here it goes back to
stallet so it goes client uicorn fast
API so it's instead of directly fast API
there's stall it in the middle it's just
that fast API is actually it's iner from
stet so it just gets all the capabil the
Starlet has to offer that sequence of
events was really helpful I appreciate
you sharing that I wanted to ask one
quick clarifying question you mentioned
a client that might be connecting to a
fast API I know that fast apis are
created in Python but is there a
restriction in terms of the programming
language that we use in order to
interact with a running fast API you
mean the client yeah no you can use any
HTP client okay in any language so the
the last thing that I wanted to talk
about when it comes to Starlet is that I
often hear people refer to Starlet as a
web micro framework what does it mean if
it is a micro framework I think the idea
of being a micro is that you can use any
part of Starlet independently you don't
necessarily need to use the Starlet
class you can use for example the
response by itself the response class by
itself because the response class is
already a web framework sorry
application so you can just use that
part you don't need to use the whole
Starlet you can use pieces of Starlet I
think that's the idea I know that many
of our listeners when they hear the
phrase web framework are probably going
to think of in the context of python
things like d Jango or flask can you
comment briefly how are D Jango and
flask connected to or different from
Fast API so I know that for example
flask in the beginning Sebastian tried
to I think he also created one package
that was flask something or trying to
improve that so they was not to create
fast API in the beginning but to improve
the current applications that like web
Frameworks that existed at the time if I
see flask in the point of view as a user
it's just very similar to develop
compared to fast API in the terms that
you use also a decorator you define what
method you have also lately I think two
years ago flas created the decorators
that you can use the HTTP method so
before you couldn't like for example
app.get app. put you didn't have that
before and I think well I like to
believe but it seems obvious because of
how popular fast API got but I think I
hope this is correct that that was
inspired by fast API because before you
had only app. root and then you had to
put the method there but in any case I
believe it's very similar to develop uh
with flask and fast API in terms of
creating the application itself I think
the difference are subtle but they
matter on the usability of the framework
like creating the application itself
like you have the type hints on Fast API
you have the automatic documentation but
you you can also have nowadays you have
some similar packages that you can use
flask with and have those capabilities
but it's not native and what I noticed
that having those things those features
natively makes a huge difference from
the user because then you don't need to
think much about how to get those things
working it's just out of the box can you
give a concrete example of something
that you would choose to use fast API to
build and then in contrast give an
example of something where maybe you
would instead prefer to use Jango or
flask oh I don't have good news here
okay I don't think I would prefer use
the Alternatives in any case but I would
know like for example I know that you
could use jungle to really nicely serve
static web applications I know that use
case also I know that people like that
they uh the jungle RM is in the same
like it's included on the jungle thing
so you have the RM you have the how to
serve files you have the jungle CSM or
something like that you have a lot of
jungle things that are again native from
the framework that people really like
but I am very used to the fast API world
so I would just use fast API for pretty
much any use case am I right in
understanding that I would primarily use
fast API for creating a rest API Pi but
if I were to build a full web
application like with a graphical
interface then that might be a case in
which I would pick Jango is that a fair
statement I think for me no but I can
see people agreeing with that because
again it's out of the box on Jungle you
don't need to think much about it like
you have even tutorials about it you
have a lot of information during the
years about this specific subject like
how to do that specific thing that you
are asking me but on Fast API you can
also serve static file just fine you
have even a static filos class that you
can serve what you intend to okay that
makes sense thanks so much for that
clarification I really appreciate it I
want to now turn our attention to some
issues connected to security two
keywords that often come up in the
context of API security are
authentication and authorization and so
my question is does fast API support
both authentication and
authorization so fast API does not
handle that for you so you need to
implement the layer yourself what it
does is you can define a way for how to
interpret some data that comes from the
request so for example you have HTTP
basic class which it's used for fast API
to get the authorization header and then
get the username and the password and it
provides that to your endpoint so you
have you use that class just to kind of
parse that they data for you but it does
not handle that for you what I mean
handle is that you don't have a logic to
verify that the user exists in the
database that's the correct password
that's something you'd have to implement
yourself there are some libraries that
are available for that I honestly
haven't used any but I have a friend
called Frankie and some numbers that has
fast API users so if you Google Fast API
users you're going to find it's a 4K
GitHub Stars project I don't know how
many users how many downloads it today
but he's a very good developer so this
is one possibility as an off library to
use with fast API okay so it sounds like
it's not that fast API natively supports
authentication and authorization but
that there are packages that you can add
on in order to make that work is that
the right way to think about it I would
say it's the same idea as flesk on flesk
you also don't have a way to like
natively do this logic like you have to
implement that yourself or you have to
use any third party library to do that
for you okay and we'll make sure to link
to the framework that you mentioned a
moment ago so that our listeners can
check it out yeah one library that I
always use is all Le yeah that's a good
one to bring up can you explain it in a
little bit of Greater detail it's helps
to do the all Logic on your application
it's just very famous there's one thing
that I don't like that they are doing
for years and then I complain and then
they don't reply to me is that they use
this config class from Starlet like to
receive two environment variables
Secrets I think or something like that
from like I use a to integrate with
GitHub I think that's my use case or
that was my use case and then they use
the config class from charlet but that's
a feature that no one uses it and it
prevents me from deprecating it so I
mean I'm saying everybody I don't know
who uses it to be completely Fair on
this but it prevents me from acting on
it because this Library used it and I
really use the library so yeah I see
what you're saying I think it's in part
making your job as a maintainer perhaps
a little bit more difficult exactly so
what I want to do now is talk a little
bit about how a programmer would
actually design and Implement and test
their own fast API since we've already
covered some of the details about how
fast API is implemented I think we're
ready to launch into the next stage of
our show so can we talk a little bit you
mentioned before I've got to write a
function that represents an end point I
have to have type annotations for that
and I think many of our listeners will
be comfortable with that process my next
question is how do I actually deploy a
fast API so I'm going to comment on that
but I want to for our listeners to go to
the fast API documentation on this
because there is a very good page if you
go to fast API you see deployments fast
API Sebastian dedicated good time on
writing those dogs and it explains in
good detail about what are your options
and how to do the deployment there are
some ways that people do the deployment
like for example there are people that
deploy only with Yorn I know that one of
the maintainers of Yorn like the one
that was previous to me now is he very
not active but he used only Yorn with
just a single process and then he said
to me yeah it's been running for a month
no problem 100 of requests it's all fine
he said it to me when we were drinking a
beer so I was like oh that's good and
then there's also recommendation on the
uorn documentation for example to use
uorn with junicorn and junicorn is also
a web server implementation more focused
on the uasi world but they also have a
process manager so the idea is that
you'd have the your uorn workers your
uorn processes being managed by junicorn
so you can also deploy with junicorn and
uicorn and what you will do is that
every time a uicorn process dies it's
going to restart that worker so that
process and then you're going to always
have that number of workers running so
for example I do I create a unicorn
youorn server with four uorn workers and
then if one dies junicorn will
automatically restart a new worker so
you always going to have four workers
during the whole lifetime of the
application so this combined approach
that you're describing now sounds like
it would be beneficial because it would
make your system more reliable is is
that the right way to understand it yeah
that's correct but also nowadays people
are using kubernetes and very fancy
Technologies so I would say that on that
world it is easy and more recommended to
use uorn with a single process because
then you have each pod will have one
process which is the uorn process and
then that's going to be your unit in the
system and you don't want to complexify
that part with junicorn in the middle
because then you're going to have the
process one it's going to be junicorn
and then you're going to have multiple
unicorn workers it gets too complex for
the need I see what you're saying I
wanted to also talk a little bit about
what a developer would do when they're
testing a fast API one of the things
that I've done is I spin up a local host
server once I have that Local Host
server running can I use things like
unit test or pie test in order to test
my fast
API well we have a test client in
stallet and IPI that you can use to test
your end points the way it does
internally is that it emulates simulates
how the networking happens but it does
not really create like you are running
everything in Python there that's just
how it happens so that would be the way
to test your fast API application but
also you have the test client from
stallet and you also have the test
client well the client from hpx which is
async client and that's the recommended
one is there a difference between using
pest to test a regular python function
or method in a program versus testing
something that comes from Fast
API um not sure if I understand the
question so the idea is many of our
listeners are probably familiar with
writing a function in Python and then
writing a py test test case or maybe a
property based test with hypothesis and
I guess my question is how would the
process for testing a fast API be
different from what they're normally
used to for something that it's just a
regular python function or method so the
way I believe things should be when you
are developing a fast API application or
any web application is that most of your
tests are going to look very similar on
which you have your entry point which
will be calling the endpoint and you're
going to always test again unexpected
output so we're going to call this
endpoint called SL potato and you expect
I don't know three potatoes to be back
and then the idea that I have on how you
should test this and I don't know if
you'd want to call it unit integration I
don't well I don't care but the idea is
that you want to test something the
input and against unexpected output
doing this trying to be like not trying
to test all the functions that are in
the middle you open space for changing
the internals without breaking the API
and also using your efforts your energy
to test
this part of the code so my idea is you
have your tests and most of them are
focused on the input and output and then
you are free to change and refactor the
code as you want but also if you have
some important logic that you want to
really unit test for example no no there
is something really important on the
system that you really need to test then
you are free to create some unit test
but the way I believes that most of the
tests on an we framework should be input
output that's it the strategy you're
suggesting makes a lot of sense if there
are listeners of our episode who want to
learn more about designing and testing
apis we'll link them to episode 387 and
episode 542 in order to get more
information now one of the things that I
would love to do in the next phase of
our show is talk with you a little bit
about your experiences of maintaining
packages like Starlet obviously you have
to think carefully about how to test
your own code in Starlet and you have to
think carefully about how you document
and you lint all of the systems that
you're building can you share with our
listeners some of your philosophies and
strategies when it comes to designing
and implementing maybe Starlet or
uvicorn or fast API so first I think I
follow the philosophy of each project
specifically so for example Starlet and
Yorn are under the encode organization
which was created by Tom and I Tred to
follow his philosophy what I mean by
this is that I always try most of the
time to if a feature is not needed on
the package and it can be a third party
package then let's go for it first let's
see how is the desire for that feature
on the world and then if it gets really
a lot of attention then we can merge the
feature into the library itself so for
example you can create a middle era in a
third party package and then if that
gets a lot of users then you can go back
to stall it and then you create a
request against it and then you have
that mer so this is the first thing but
for example pantic is more permissive on
the amount of B requests so for example
we create this ptic extra types which
accepts a lot of types accepts a lot of
new types to be added on the library so
it really depends on the project one of
the things I noticed on the fast API
documentation is that it specifically
says that the code base is 100% type
annotated and actually its test Suite
has 100% test coverage why might that be
a goal for the people who are
maintaining the fast API system or other
open source
Frameworks I think it proves something
at least I believe that well I am a
strong believer of the number 100
anything that is less than that I do not
think it's a good number I've heard many
times on on lot of companies people
saying oh don't worry we have a pretty
high coverage we have 85% but then you
start looking and actually the most
important things are not tested so it
really doesn't matter and I think the
what I really believe is the 100% clean
coverage where you aim for the 100%
you're going to do the 100% but you're
going to proactively choose when to not
have something tested and the idea is
that when you write the ignor of on
those lines that you don't want to test
wow you're doing it that actively so you
are making sure that you don't want to
test that so that just makes sure that
the library is in a better State than it
could be one of the things that I've
learned about fast API is that it's
something that really enhances developer
productivity I find it incredibly easy
to make an API and then get it up and
running and have it deployed what were
some of the strategies that the fast API
team developed in order to ensure that
actually creating an API with fast API
was fun and it was something that
enhanced developer productivity you mean
strategy well you might not have
necessarily had a strategy per se but in
your experience
what is it about fast API that makes it
something that enhances developer
productivity and makes it so easy to get
up and running and ship an API I think
it's because people care about developer
experience and when I say people I mean
the maintainers of the libraries that
are related so I think Sebastian cares a
lot about Dev experience I think Samuel
as well I think I do as well so I think
putting the maintainers of those related
packages in like how you see them if you
work with them you see that like they
are bothered if something takes one more
second to do or one more step they're
just bothered about that thing
so everything is around this philosophy
of doing things that maybe faster but
have a better developer experience can
you give a concrete example of what an
enhanced developer productivity
experience would look like yeah so for
example F API has the parameters which
you have the types on it you need to
have the types on it otherwise you're
going to have an error so you put the
right type and you are sure that's the
right information you're going to
receive from the request and then you
have automatic like out completion on
your ID so that's one thing that saves a
lot of time because well you have out
completion so you don't need to think
about what's right there yeah that's a
really good point and I've had exactly
that experience myself as well I wanted
to also ask you a question about your
experiences you've had a lot of years
invested in things like Starlet and
uicorn and fast API have there been some
aha moments or some lessons that you can
pass along to other developers like what
was something that you learned that was
somewhat
unexpected I learned that sometimes you
need to be patient you need to wait and
see if something is really worth it
futurewise sometimes getting too excited
it's a problem people are actually more
unhappy about things that change than
things that continue the same even if
they are not the best thing so when
trying to improve something you need to
be careful to not break other people's
apis and not break the current way of
the way they were doing things wow
that's an awesome Insight is there
something that we haven't talked about
in the context of fast API that you
think we should discuss in Greater
Detail no I think I think we talk plenty
yeah no it's good all right so in our
episode we've covered a lot of the key
Concepts associated with apis and fast
apis then we dove into how fast API was
actually implemented and then we've
learned some strategies for actually
creating testing and deploying a fast
API thank you for sharing all of those
insights I really appreciate it thank
you for having me here as a conclusion
to our show do you have a call to action
for our listeners in case they want to
learn more about fast API or get started
with this framework yeah read the ducks
the ducks are amazing go for it all
right I have to Echo that comment the
docks are absolutely amazing we'll make
sure to link to those in the show so let
me say again thank you this has really
been an awesome conversation I hope that
you have enjoyed the conversation if
you're a listener Marcelo thank you for
being here on software engineering radio
thank you very much it was great okay
this is Gregory cap hammer and I'm
signing off for software engineering
radio goodbye everyone
bye-bye thanks for listening to SC radio
an educational program brought to you by
I Tri software magazine for more about
the podcast including other episodes
visit our website at se-
radio.net to provide feedback you can
comment on each episode on the website
or reach us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter
or through our slack Channel at
seo. slack.com you can also email us at
team
e-r. this and all other episodes of SC
radio is licensed under Creative Commons
license
2.5 thanks for listening